<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>faux tequila &#8211; Doug and Ruth.com</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/faux-tequila/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Life, presented as though it were a series of vacations and parties.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 23:07:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Halloween 2011: Dia de los Muertos</title>
		<link>/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 13:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faux tequila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piñata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pneumatic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self established order]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skeleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dia de los Muertos: The Day of the Dead, as celebrated in Mexico and selected Central American countries. We made it come to life with an exploding piñata and dancing skeletons. Just like they have in Mexico. The dancing skeletons idea came from a clever bit of animation Ruth found on the web. With an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dia de los Muertos: The Day of the Dead, as celebrated in Mexico and selected Central American countries. We made it come to life with an exploding <a href="http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=683" target="_blank">piñata </a>and dancing skeletons. Just like they have in Mexico.</p>
 [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] 
<p>The dancing skeletons idea came from a <a href="http://www.vivacalaca.com/eng/" target="_blank">clever bit of animation</a> Ruth found on the web. With an unlimited schedule and budget, it would have been cool to completely re-animate the video in three dimensional form. Since we are not independently wealthy, we decided to create some moving props to go along with the video itself.</p>
<p>In its final form, the video was cut down to a minute and half and projected on the front of the house while three skeletons got to pogo up and down on pneumatic cylinders. To add a bit of shock value to the presentation, a faux case of tequila was set out front to open and snap shut.</p>
 [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] 
<p>Things that amazed us #1: We didn&#8217;t see any children get scared by the tequila box, but we scared the crap out of a couple of adults. Maybe the kids expected something to happen. Maybe we just missed seeing it.</p>
<p>With the weather being what it was, we really did not expect a big turn-out. Monday morning, Doug went out to shovel the front lawn only to find that it was frozen solid. Setbacks were anticipated, but this was a new one.</p>
 [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] 
<p>The snow eventually softened-up to the point that it could be scraped off the grass leaving a wet, almost muddy mess combined with water dripping off the roof. With everything this year being either made out of paper or having 110V running through it, or both, we had some serious concerns.</p>
<p>The original plan was to decorate much more fiesta-like. Some of the lighting had to be jettisoned and paper flags remained indoors, but we were able to put down enough plywood to keep things dry. The end result was a bit creepier— fine for Halloween and possibly helpful in integrating our bizarre set-up with our neighbor&#8217;s more traditional displays.</p>
 [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] 
<p>Things that amazed us #2: Our neighbors confirmed that this was the second most popular theme we&#8217;ve used. The first? <a href="http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=368" target="_blank">Giant Floating Eyeballs</a>. No idea why. Giant Floating Eyeballs isn&#8217;t even a theme.</p>
<p>By late afternoon Ruth was able to firmly plant the papier-mâché skeletons in the ground on PVC pipe. El Burro del Diablo had been hung and the skeletons were dancing along to their music video. 247 kids later we concluded it was <em>the </em>most fun Halloween ever. Watching trick-or-treaters hit the piñata was a blast.</p>
<p><iframe width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q7s6KBEpaUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Things that amazed us #3: We expected kids to either aggressively pursue hitting the piñata or shy away, but most of the time they were shockingly analytical and courteous to each other. We witnessed a group of eight-year-olds employ &#8220;Eeny, meeny, miny, moe&#8221; <strong></strong> to pseudo randomize the order in which they would get to hit the piñata. They then lined up in their self established order. Bizarre.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve had some time to reflect on Halloween themes and coincidentally Ruth has been investigating smoke ring machines a la <a href="http://disneyworld.disney.go.com/parks/magic-kingdom/attractions/many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/" target="_blank">Disney&#8217;s Winnie the Pooh</a> attraction. Maybe we&#8217;ll have a Heffalumps and Woozles theme next year. Or not. Having a theme isn&#8217;t important&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
