<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Rush &#8211; Doug and Ruth.com</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/rush/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Life, presented as though it were a series of vacations and parties.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 13:41:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Halloween 2009: Gigantic Floating Eyeballs</title>
		<link>/gigantic-floating-eyeballs-halloween-night/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 00:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amplification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rush]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We gave out candy to 196 kids plus one father in a Rush concert shirt. A good night by anyone&#8217;s standard. And technologically, it was a thing of beauty. I have to say that the start of the evening was looking grim. The wind had picked up. The whole rig was in danger of becoming [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We gave out candy to 196 kids plus one father in a Rush concert shirt. A good night by anyone&#8217;s standard. And technologically, it was a thing of beauty.</p>
<p>I have to say that the start of the evening was looking grim. The wind had picked up. The whole rig was in danger of becoming a sail. My neighbor was still mocking me about the fantastic set of hooters I had constructed above the doorway. Then the sun went over the horizon and all was good.</p>
<p>The video screens lit up and the sound was turned on. It all just&#8230; worked. As if I had just gone out and bought the system at some yuppie Halloween superstore (something I was accused of several times).</p>
<p>The key thing here is, in fact, the sound. Yes the eyeballs have sound. No it doesn&#8217;t make any sense, but it&#8217;s just one of those things I&#8217;ve learned that everything must have a sound to have an identity. So I gave it a voice and you can hear it in the video below. The other thing I have learned is that there is no substitute for proper amplification. This year I employed the Roland <a href="http://www.rolandus.com/products/productdetails.php?ProductId=583&amp;ParentId=33" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KC-350</a> combo amp which made the house shake. It could be heard a block away. It made dogs howl.</p>
<p>Anyway, kids were truly mesmerized. I&#8217;m used to the parents wanting to take a second look, but children actually delayed their pursuit of sugar to stand and stare. There is no higher complement.</p>
<p>Thanks to all who dropped by. For those who couldn&#8217;t, this please enjoy the video. And don&#8217;t forget to turn the sound up.</p>
 [<a href="/gigantic-floating-eyeballs-halloween-night/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] 
 [<a href="/gigantic-floating-eyeballs-halloween-night/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] 


<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Halloween 2009: Gigantic Floating Eyeballs" width="620" height="465" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fFzAYIpZSww?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
