<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>skeleton &#8211; Doug and Ruth.com</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/skeleton/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Life, presented as though it were a series of vacations and parties.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 14:18:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Halloween 2020: Le Petit Chien Qui Fait Caca</title>
		<link>/halloween-2020-le-petit-chien-qui-fait-caca/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 20:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Audio FX Mini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childish humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G8]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PIC-IO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[retroreflective sensors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skeleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wiener dog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=2260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writing the title in French is a poor attempt at classing-up this year&#8217;s Halloween theme. You will quickly see past that because this year we leaned in hard on childish humor. There&#8217;s no covering it up. 2020 being what it is, it seemed problematic to do something scary. Not that a good scare would be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="tw-target-text">Writing the title in French is a poor attempt at classing-up this year&#8217;s Halloween theme. You will quickly see past that because this year we leaned in hard on childish humor. There&#8217;s no covering it up.</p>



<p>2020 being what it is, it seemed problematic to do something scary. Not that a good scare would be inappropriate. It seemed inappropriate to do the expected or the usual. In a year when nothing is usual, it felt like a little levity was needed. To that point, we give you <em>The Little Pooping Dog</em>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Pooping Dog Halloween 2020" width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XZ2iEV0dZpY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>We had already started building our intended theme: A highly interactive multi-media display with several tactile components. Then it sank-in that anything involving touching wasn&#8217;t going to fly. Moreover, Halloween itself was in question. Putting more time and money into a project that would encourage people to group together seemed misguided. Then we saw the candy chute.</p>



<p>Some genius came up with the idea of simply sliding the candy down to kids through a pipe. Not only is sliding the candy more civilized than chucking the candy at them or using a slingshot, the pipe itself can be decorated to make the method of transport more festive! But <em>how </em>to decorate?</p>



<p>At some point we were talking about just putting out a talking skeleton from <a href="http://dougandruth.com/blog/halloween-2017-pirates-part-deux/" data-type="post" data-id="2227">our last use of a talking skeleton</a> and calling it a day. Never mind that it&#8217;s a pirate skeleton. We are way past helping people make sense of things. But what if the skeleton pirate had a skeleton dog with him?</p>



<p>Why this made sense at the time no longer matters. The fact that a skeleton dog <a href="https://amazon.com/gp/product/B07W834BTZ" data-type="URL" data-id="https://amazon.com/gp/product/B07W834BTZ">could easily be acquired</a> and that the dog was able to straddle the pipe such that the dog appeared to be crapping out candy, appeared to us like comedy gold.</p>



<p>By the way, a wiener dog? It just doesn&#8217;t get any better and the suggestion for temperament from more conservative advisors was justifiably ignored.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s get down to brass tacks. If the pirate is going to talk, the dog needs to fart, right? The pirate had already been wired-up with an <a href="https://www.adafruit.com/product/2342" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.adafruit.com/product/2342">Adafruit Audio FX</a> sound board. Luckily, the sound board could be programmed to take triggers from more than one input, so it could have one sensor for activating the pirate spiel and another sensor for detecting the passing (out) of candy.</p>



<p>The light weight of the candy put into question the use of a physical limit switch. Since we were already using a retroreflective light sensor for the pirate, it seemed reasonable to use a <a href="https://amazon.com/gp/product/B073WQV3D9" data-type="URL" data-id="https://amazon.com/gp/product/B073WQV3D9">short-range light sensor</a> for the candy.</p>



<p>By now you&#8217;re probably already seeing a problem. The sensor has a reset time of &lt;2.5 ms. The Audio FX board requires a 200 ms pulse to activate playback. If the candy is moving at 2 m/s, a typical &#8220;fun size&#8221; candy bar is going to pass over the detector for only 20 ms. What we need is a pulse stretcher.</p>



<p>Fortunately, we had an old <a href="https://www.olimex.com/Products/PIC/Development/PIC-IO/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.olimex.com/Products/PIC/Development/PIC-IO/">Olimex PIC-IO board</a> laying around that could be programmed to turn 20 ms pulses into 200 ms; thus, ensuring that each candy bar would trigger the audio. Sure, we might have gotten away with using a capacitor and a couple of diodes, but we are software people by trade and using the microcontroller made absolute sure the dog would fart.</p>



<p>Over the course of the night we got 140 kids &#8211; about 100 short of a typical night. Still, it was great to see that many people out in the fresh air. The danger is real, but our neighbors were committed to find safe ways to trick-or-treat. For the parents and kids that ventured out, we hope that the laugh was worth as least as much as the candy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Pooping Dog Halloween (day view)" width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Psxv5bmUDsk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halloween 2016: The Headhunter&#8217;s Jungle Hut</title>
		<link>/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cinematography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canon 7D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piezo trigger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samplers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[show controllers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shrunken head]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skeleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony Vegas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tiki torches]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=2193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have been wanting to improve on our 2007 Tiki theme. That&#160; year we made a giant African mask. The mask spoke and rolled its eyes and we planned on using those features to create a circus barker-like character in a somewhat elaborate interactive display. The show didn&#8217;t make it as far as we wanted. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have been wanting to improve on our <a href="http://dougandruth.com/blog/halloween-2007/">2007 Tiki theme</a>. That&nbsp; year we made a giant African mask. The mask spoke and rolled its eyes and we planned on using those features to create a circus barker-like character in a somewhat elaborate interactive display.</p>
<p>The show didn&#8217;t make it as far as we wanted. They never do, but this year we scrapped the interactive elements and the production became an exercise in set decoration. The porch was clad with reed fencing and jungle vines. Shrunken heads on bamboo pikes. Two Maori warrior shields. Or at least our interpretation of what a vaguely Polynesian warrior&#8217;s shield should look like.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>There is some debate as to how far <a href="http://tikiloungetalk.com/tiki-culture/">tiki</a> should stray from Polynesian culture. To be authentically tiki, the environment must be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mysterious</li>
<li>Exotic</li>
<li>Richly detailed</li>
</ul>
<p>Our take on tiki is that in addition to the above it must be comfortable or romantic and include anything that might wash up on a tropical beach. Over all it must be a form of escapism. Start with a South Pacific island, imagine what floats in from South America, Japan, India and Africa. Then light a torch and pour a drink. That&#8217;s tiki.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>Our incorporation of tiki into Halloween was only half intuitive. The dark and mysterious aspects are well suited, but the exotic parts not so much. We decided that defining the story to be about headhunters would make the theme more palatable to kids.</p>
<p>For the music, we went straight to <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=exotica+music&amp;ie=utf-8&amp;oe=utf-8">exotica</a>. Les Baxter, Martin Denney, <a href="http://www.leftaobuddha.com/">The Left Arm of Buddha</a>, and <a href="http://www.tikiyakiorchestra.com/">The Tikiyaki Orchestra</a>. Is this what a headhunter listens to? Doesn&#8217;t matter. Slower tempo songs added to the feeling of mystery and suspense. The genre speaks the language of adventure and &#8211; somewhat surprisingly &#8211; it is decipherable by people of any age.</p>
<p>When adding detail, shadow is as important as light. With vines covering the doorway, the darkened space behind added as much to the suspense as the foreground elements. We tried to make the body of the house as dark as possible to put focus on the themed elements. The most detailed element being the jack-o-lantern pineapple tucked into the corner of the porch. It was the kind of Easter egg that makes tiki great.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>We did make a couple contributions to technology. The first were musical warrior shields. Each shield make a sound when hit. This was a subtle feature that no one picked up on unless shown, but it was fun for little kids. Each shield had a piezo trigger connected to an electronic percussion controller. The controller triggered the &#8220;Tiki Threat&#8221; patch on an E-mu Proteus sound module. Good old 90&#8217;s music technology made even better for having an obviously named sound choice.</p>
<p>The other new feature were the self-flaring tiki torches. There is nothing that a little propane can&#8217;t fix. Just add a solenoid valve, a regulator, and some copper tubing and you&#8217;re off to the races. They were connected to the VenueMagic show control system that gave all the lighting a soft, flame flicker. The occasional burst of flame kept people ready for the unexpected.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>Out of the 258 kids to come up our stairs, about half correctly identified the theme as &#8220;tiki.&#8221; That&#8217;s impressive. Tiki is most often identified with adult diversions, but it creeps into pop culture everywhere. It wouldn&#8217;t be a surprise if children picked it up from a trip to Disney World or an old episode of Scooby Doo. Wherever they got it, the theme was much better received than we planned.</p>
<p><iframe width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jIzt1hxouFA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2016-the-headhunters-jungle-hut/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halloween 2015: Yet Another Talking Skeleton</title>
		<link>/halloween-2015-yet-another-talking-skeleton/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 03:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cinematography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canon 7D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoPro Hero 3+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interactive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[show controllers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skeleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony Vegas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=2137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Choosing a theme for Halloween is an annual challenge. Time constraints in recent years have tempted us into punting; at least to the extent that our theme becomes diluted into &#8220;do something scary.&#8221; Technology is often the catalyst. We started off decidedly low-tech with the purchase of a sharkstooth scrim remnant. We had enough material [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> [<a href="/halloween-2015-yet-another-talking-skeleton/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>Choosing a theme for Halloween is an annual challenge. Time constraints in recent years have tempted us into punting; at least to the extent that our theme becomes diluted into &#8220;do something scary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Technology is often the catalyst. We started off decidedly low-tech with the purchase of a <a href="http://www.rosebrand.com/fabric-stage-curtains-backdrops/sharkstooth-scrim-fabrics.aspx">sharkstooth scrim</a> remnant. We had enough material to cover the doorway or a large prop, but using the scrim requires control over lighting near the house.</p>
<p>Scrim can be made opaque by shining a light on it at an oblique angle. By changing the lighting, the scrim can be made transparent; thus, revealing the area behind. To get the lighting right, you pretty much need to start out with complete darkness. Streetlights near out house make that difficult.</p>
<p>The solution (as if this were a problem requiring a solution) was to stretch the scrim vertically. We were then free to hide something scary above the heads of the unsuspecting trick-or-treaters. That scary thing would be a talking skeleton.</p>
<p>We already owned a skeleton with a servo controlled jaw, but it is heavy and advancements in skeleton technology using space-age lightweight materials made the purchase of a new skeleton an imperative. This made hanging the skeleton easier. Hanging the scrim required building a steel frame around the porch. That took way too much time.</p>
<p>The lighting could have been controlled in a number of kludgy, hacked-up ways, but it seemed like an investment was in order. Since we try to make the display as interactive as possible, we decided to buy <a href="https://www.venuemagic.com/">VenueMagic</a>, a software show controller. VenueMagic makes it very easy to add lighting and music cues that can be triggered by pressure mats and light beam sensors.</p>
<p>The triggers were attached to the 90&#8217;s era Maris hardware show controller we got off eBay a few years ago. The Maris is a pain in the butt to program, but it is easy enough to make it send a MIDI message when a trigger is tripped. VenueMagic uses the MIDI message to cue lighting on the stairs, sound effects and ultimately, the skeleton gag.</p>
<p>We also got additional amplification providing four 200 watt channels of audio. The dialog, music and sound effects were mixed into three channels. The dialog starts at the center channel then is spread to the side channels after a thunder and lightning cue. The thunder was set to &#8220;maximum impact&#8221; volume and that took out the small speakers in the yard. The speakers were replaced just before the witching hour.</p>
<p>We still had one channel left. At the last second we decided to add a cat screech next to the stairs. The cat, which took less than an hour to setup, would become the big scare of the display.</p>
<p>We had about 220 kids this year &#8211; a little less than last year. The display ended up being more fun than scary and the entire experience was less than a minute long. But we had fans &#8211; a pack of little girls who visited so many times that they ultimately tried to scare us. That made it worthwhile.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PXV5iz021E8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
