<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>video &#8211; Doug and Ruth.com</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/video/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Life, presented as though it were a series of vacations and parties.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 16:23:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Halloween 2019: Bats</title>
		<link>/halloween-2019-bats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 01:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canon 7D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LG G6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microcontrollers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PIC-IO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repeatability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sprite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=2231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last couple of years has caused us to undertake a review of our technical capabilities. Too much had gone wrong or become unreliable. While the theme is usually our chief concern, this year the goal was to lock-down some of the basic building blocks of our theatrical show system. The first item was video. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The last couple of years has caused us to undertake a review of our technical capabilities. Too much had gone wrong or become unreliable. While the theme is usually our chief concern, this year the goal was to lock-down some of the basic building blocks of our theatrical show system.</p>



<p>The first item was video. The video is played back on a <a href="https://www.frightprops.com/video-visual-effects/digital-video-players/sprite-seamless-looping-hd-triggerable-video-player.html">MedeaWiz Sprite</a> with a DMX interface. We had tried to use video last year and it failed miserably because of a bad cable connection. It was a stupid problem to have, so that got addressed. But how to use it? A quick search of Halloween related videos on the Internet results in the idea of making bats fly out of the doorway.</p>



<p>Creating the video was fairly straightforward, but the key to making it feel creepy was in the audio. Without the sound, the images looked a bit like a Rorschach test. They needed that squeaky sound that bats make to add context. More importantly, it needed to sound like the bats were getting closer.</p>



<p>To make the bats sound menacing, multiple tracks were played across five channels of surround sound. The most distant chirping sounds were at the corners of the house. Closer-up were large wing flapping sounds nearest to the stairs. The wing flapping was not a real bat sound, but the idea of a bat flying close to your head.</p>



<p>The last channel was placed across the street. We used long-range Bluetooth to transmit the bats sounds to a speaker in our neighbor&#8217;s yard. This is a technical advance we will probably use in the future because it really messed with people. It was fun to watch people during the first three seconds of the video where they thought: There are bats. The bats are coming at me. The bats are everywhere.</p>



<p>One new piece of tech that we will definitely use every year was a new light beam trigger. We have used a light beam at the base of the stairs to start the show for years, but it always had the problem of re-triggering the show when people exited. We used to mitigate this problem by adding a delay before the show could be restarted, but that works only if people arrive at given rate.</p>



<p>The new trigger has two light beams. This is similar to the electronic turnstiles Disney used about a decade ago. A microcontroller board was programmed to check the order in which the beams were broken so we could determine the direction of movement. Going up the stairs starts the bat video. Going down the stairs made a cat screeching sound &#8211; just because we could.</p>



<p>Lastly, we upgraded our speaker system. The new speakers are more weather resistant and handle a lot more power. This was needed to reduce stress as much as wanting to improve sound quality. Rain is inevitable and this year was a perfect example. It was nice to have the speakers out all day in the rain without worrying about them. It was also nice to drive the smaller speakers by the stairs as hard a we wanted to.</p>



<p>The video below was mixed to be in surround sound, but YouTube re-mixes it down to stereo, so you can&#8217;t really get the full effect. Next time we invite you over, make sure to ask to see the version on the home server.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube aligncenter wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio wp-embed-aspect-16-9"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Bats Halloween 2019" width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uber7FydMFM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube aligncenter wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Testing the Directional Beam Trigger" width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XuKWYFUxLa4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Halloween 2011: Dia de los Muertos</title>
		<link>/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 13:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faux tequila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piñata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pneumatic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self established order]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skeleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dia de los Muertos: The Day of the Dead, as celebrated in Mexico and selected Central American countries. We made it come to life with an exploding piñata and dancing skeletons. Just like they have in Mexico. The dancing skeletons idea came from a clever bit of animation Ruth found on the web. With an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dia de los Muertos: The Day of the Dead, as celebrated in Mexico and selected Central American countries. We made it come to life with an exploding <a href="http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=683" target="_blank">piñata </a>and dancing skeletons. Just like they have in Mexico.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>The dancing skeletons idea came from a <a href="http://www.vivacalaca.com/eng/" target="_blank">clever bit of animation</a> Ruth found on the web. With an unlimited schedule and budget, it would have been cool to completely re-animate the video in three dimensional form. Since we are not independently wealthy, we decided to create some moving props to go along with the video itself.</p>
<p>In its final form, the video was cut down to a minute and half and projected on the front of the house while three skeletons got to pogo up and down on pneumatic cylinders. To add a bit of shock value to the presentation, a faux case of tequila was set out front to open and snap shut.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>Things that amazed us #1: We didn&#8217;t see any children get scared by the tequila box, but we scared the crap out of a couple of adults. Maybe the kids expected something to happen. Maybe we just missed seeing it.</p>
<p>With the weather being what it was, we really did not expect a big turn-out. Monday morning, Doug went out to shovel the front lawn only to find that it was frozen solid. Setbacks were anticipated, but this was a new one.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>The snow eventually softened-up to the point that it could be scraped off the grass leaving a wet, almost muddy mess combined with water dripping off the roof. With everything this year being either made out of paper or having 110V running through it, or both, we had some serious concerns.</p>
<p>The original plan was to decorate much more fiesta-like. Some of the lighting had to be jettisoned and paper flags remained indoors, but we were able to put down enough plywood to keep things dry. The end result was a bit creepier— fine for Halloween and possibly helpful in integrating our bizarre set-up with our neighbor&#8217;s more traditional displays.</p>
<p> [<a href="/halloween-2011-dia-de-los-muertos/">See image gallery at localhost</a>] </p>
<p>Things that amazed us #2: Our neighbors confirmed that this was the second most popular theme we&#8217;ve used. The first? <a href="http://dougandruth.com/blog/?p=368" target="_blank">Giant Floating Eyeballs</a>. No idea why. Giant Floating Eyeballs isn&#8217;t even a theme.</p>
<p>By late afternoon Ruth was able to firmly plant the papier-mâché skeletons in the ground on PVC pipe. El Burro del Diablo had been hung and the skeletons were dancing along to their music video. 247 kids later we concluded it was <em>the </em>most fun Halloween ever. Watching trick-or-treaters hit the piñata was a blast.</p>
<p><iframe width="620" height="349" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q7s6KBEpaUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Things that amazed us #3: We expected kids to either aggressively pursue hitting the piñata or shy away, but most of the time they were shockingly analytical and courteous to each other. We witnessed a group of eight-year-olds employ &#8220;Eeny, meeny, miny, moe&#8221; <strong></strong> to pseudo randomize the order in which they would get to hit the piñata. They then lined up in their self established order. Bizarre.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve had some time to reflect on Halloween themes and coincidentally Ruth has been investigating smoke ring machines a la <a href="http://disneyworld.disney.go.com/parks/magic-kingdom/attractions/many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/" target="_blank">Disney&#8217;s Winnie the Pooh</a> attraction. Maybe we&#8217;ll have a Heffalumps and Woozles theme next year. Or not. Having a theme isn&#8217;t important&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
